<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a">The Commentary of Yefet ben ʿEli the Karaite on the Book of Ruth / פירושו של יפת בן עלי הקראי למגילת רות</title>
                <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East / ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/4WHPBUN3/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-06-07+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-06-07+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <analytic>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Sagit</forename>
                        <surname>Butbul</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="a">The Commentary of Yefet ben ʿEli the Karaite on the Book of Ruth / פירושו של יפת בן עלי הקראי למגילת רות</title>
                    <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/4WHPBUN3</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/4WHPBUN3</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/4WHPBUN3</idno>
                    <ref target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/23415037"/>
                </analytic>
                <monogr>
                    <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East / ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                    <imprint>
                        <date>2003</date>
                    </imprint>
                    <biblScope unit="pp">459-571</biblScope>
                    <biblScope unit="vol">N.S. 8 (23)</biblScope>
                </monogr>
                <note type="abstract">Publisher's Abstract: Yefet ben Eli, who lived in Jerusalem during the second half of the 10th century and beginning of the eleventh, is one of the foremost Karaite Bible exegetes. Yefet translated and commented upon the entire Hebrew Bible. That his works continued to have an impact on later generations is evident from the numerous posthumous copies of his commentaries. The British Library in London houses a unique collection of Karaite manuscripts, including a series of twenty biblical manuscripts written in Arabic characters and containing the Arabic commentaries of Yefet ben ʿEli. One of these, MS BL Or. 2554, contains Yefet's translation and commentary on the Book of Ruth and the Song of Songs. According to the colophon, this particular manuscript was copied in Ramla in the year 395 A.H. (= 1004/5 A.D.), during Yefet's lifetime. This article presents a complete edition of Yefet's translation and commentary on the Book of Ruth, accompanied by an annotated Hebrew translation and a glossary of the rare terms and phrases found in the commentary. The edition is based on manuscript BL Or. 2554 due to its significance and, primarily, its reliability. However, as this manuscript is not complete, other manuscripts were used in order to fill lacunae. The commentary is preceded by an introduction in which several topics are discussed at length. In addition to a survey of the rabbinic and Karaite sources used by Yefet, the introduction also includes a description of the various manuscripts that were used to complement Yefet's commentary and a survey of earlier studies devoted to Yefet's commentary on the Book of Ruth.</note>
                <citedRange>Hey, this one has kids!</citedRange>
            </biblStruct>
            <listRelation/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>