<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a">On the Arabic Translation of the Torah by Issāchār ben-Sūsān Hamma'arāvī || על תרגום התורה לערבית של ר' יששכר בן-סוסאן המערבי</title>
                <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="associate" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/E2JBQC36/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-10-10+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-10-10+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <analytic>
                    <author>
                        <forename>David</forename>
                        <surname>Doron</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="a">On the Arabic Translation of the Torah by Issāchār ben-Sūsān Hamma'arāvī || על תרגום התורה לערבית של ר' יששכר בן-סוסאן המערבי</title>
                    <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/E2JBQC36</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/E2JBQC36</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/E2JBQC36</idno>
                    <ref target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/23414831"/>
                </analytic>
                <monogr>
                    <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                    <imprint>
                        <date>1985</date>
                    </imprint>
                    <biblScope unit="pp">279-298</biblScope>
                    <biblScope unit="vol">NS 3</biblScope>
                </monogr>
                <note type="abstract">Publisher abstract: This study is a survey of R. Issāchār ben-Sūsān Hamma'arāvī's Arabic translation of the Pentateuch: 'Al-sharḥ al-Sūsānī likhamsat jzā' al-Torāh,' according to his autograph, MS. Sassoon 159 (now MS. British Museum Or. 14020 A). Ben-Sūsān, who flourished in the sixteenth century, immigrated in his youth to Palestine from Fez in Morocco, and lived for most of his life in Safed, serving as a Rabbi in the Maghrebine congregation there. Apart from his work 'Tīqqūn Issāchār', for which he is best known, and which dealt with the intercalation of the calendar and various customs, he translated the Bible into Arabic in 1570-1574. At this time, the former connection with Islamic culture had already weakened considerably, while the dialectical basis of the language prevailed. Only a very little material of this period has been investigated, and it is therefore important to examine texts which are likely to shed light on the linguistic lines and directions of development of the time. In his introduction to the translation, ben-Sūsān portrays the background of his rendering: the version of R. Sa'adia Ga'on was no longer intelligible to his contemporaries, and not even to scholars, because of its literary style, and because of the changes which R. Sa'adia Ga'on adopted in connection with the Biblical word-order and its phrasing. It was therefore neglected and as a result, ignorance increased among Arabic-speaking Jews. Ben-Sūsān also delineates his method, which is mainly a literal translation, to the benefit of both teachers and pupils, because of the need to memorize word for word, as had heretofore been the custom among Jews. Moreover, since Ben-Sūsān was aware that spoken Arabic was so ramified and differed from place to place, he included at the end of each section a 'bayān' — an explanation and a discussion of various words. The article analyzes the linguistic characteristics of the composition and their various strata, evaluating the translator's success in creating a suitable translation for his generation. The linguistic picture portrayed is that of an artificial language, conforming to the word order of the Bible and reliant on the earlier Judeo-Arabic tradition, which is partly anchored in classical Arabic. The Arabic in ben-Sūsān's work is neither Maghrebine nor Palestinian. It is a mixed language in which are combined, in addition to the literal infrastructure and the dialectical phenomena, other factors as well. The influence of R. Sa'adia Ga'on's translation is pervasive.</note>
            </biblStruct>
            <bibl type="formatted" subtype="https://www.zotero.org/styles/chicago-note-bibliography-16th-edition">
  Doron, David. “On the Arabic Translation of the Torah by Issāchār ben-Sūsān Hamma’arāvī || על תרגום התורה לערבית של ר’ יששכר בן-סוסאן המערבי.” <title level="m">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title> NS 3 (1985): 279–98. http://www.jstor.org/stable/23414831.
</bibl>
            <listRelation/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>