<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a">The Adaptations of R. Saadya Gaon's Bible Translation in the East ||העיבודים של תרגום ר' סעדיה גאון לתנ"ך במזרח</title>
                <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="associate" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/rvollandt">rvollandt</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record edited in Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/rvollandt">rvollandt</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/F7DEFEQL/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-10-10+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-10-10+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <analytic>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Yitzhaq</forename>
                        <surname>Avishur</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="a">The Adaptations of R. Saadya Gaon's Bible Translation in the East ||העיבודים של תרגום ר' סעדיה גאון לתנ"ך במזרח</title>
                    <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/F7DEFEQL</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/F7DEFEQL</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/F7DEFEQL</idno>
                    <ref target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/23414907"/>
                </analytic>
                <monogr>
                    <title level="j">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title>
                    <imprint>
                        <date>1991</date>
                    </imprint>
                    <biblScope unit="pp">181-202</biblScope>
                    <biblScope unit="vol">N.S. 5</biblScope>
                </monogr>
                <note type="abstract">Publisher's Abstract: Saadya Gaon's monumental translation of the Bible to Arabic was well received by Arabic speaking Jews throughout the diaspora from Iraq to Spain. Everywhere that it reached it left its impact on the study of the Bible and its interpretation. New translations to Judaeo-Arabic were hardly ever written among rabbinite Jews. Some Judaeo-Arabic Pentateuch translations written in Eastern Jewish communities are neither copies of Saadya's translation nor new ones (such as those found in printed editions, manuscripts and tape recordings of recent generations). These manuscripts are neither early nor late and range over 400 years (from the 14th—17th centuries). This group of manuscripts includes five Pentateuchs, two from Iraq, one from Syria, one from Safed and one from North Africa or Spain. The writers of these manuscripts who found Saadya's translation difficult did not abandon it, but found novel ways of dealing with it. They copied down chapters, passages, verses, collections and single works, changed the form and adapted it to the needs of their own generation. The writer suggests that these translations be called "adaptations of Saadya's translation." Yet those who did the work did not consider it an adaptation, but rather a new translation replacing an old one that was no longer adequate. If we remember that in the Middle Ages there was no great awarencess of "citing one's sources"; the use made of Saadya's translation was the same as that made of much other material. This group of manuscripts has great importance; on the one hand it makes a great contribution to the understanding of the text of Saadya's translation and the clarification of its textual history and on the other hand contibutes to the clarification and processes of new translations in the East. New translations from both Eastern and North Africa communities as well display remnants of Saadya's translation and evidently the translators did not make direct use of that translation, but only concepts and terminology which infiltrate the oral study of the Bible and from oral study to written versions of the Bible in Judaeo-Arabic.</note>
            </biblStruct>
            <bibl type="formatted" subtype="https://www.zotero.org/styles/chicago-note-bibliography-16th-edition">
  Avishur, Yitzhaq. “The Adaptations of R. Saadya Gaon’s Bible Translation in the East ||העיבודים של תרגום ר’ סעדיה גאון לתנ"ך במזרח.” <title level="m">Sefunot: Studies and Sources on the History of the Jewish Communities in the East || ספונות: מחקרים ומקורות לתולדות קהילות ישראל במזרח</title> N.S. 5 (1991): 181–202. http://www.jstor.org/stable/23414907.
</bibl>
            <listRelation/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>