<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m">Veiling Esther, Unveiling Her Story: The Reception of a Biblical Book in Islamic Lands</title>
                <title level="s">Oxford Studies in the Abrahamic Religions</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/I9IEMR7Z/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-06-07+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-06-07+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <monogr>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Adam J.</forename>
                        <surname>Silverstein</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="m">Veiling Esther, Unveiling Her Story: The Reception of a Biblical Book in Islamic Lands</title>
                    <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/I9IEMR7Z</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/I9IEMR7Z</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/I9IEMR7Z</idno>
                    <imprint>
                        <pubPlace>Oxford, New York</pubPlace>
                        <publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
                        <date>2018-11-29</date>
                    </imprint>
                </monogr>
                <series>
                    <title level="s">Oxford Studies in the Abrahamic Religions</title>
                </series>
                <note type="abstract">Veiling Esther, Unveiling Her Story: The Reception of a Biblical Book in Islamic Lands examines the ways in which the Biblical Book of Esther was read, understood, and used in Muslim lands, from ancient to modern times. It focuses on case studies covering works from various periods and regions of the Muslim world, including the Qur'an, pre-modern historical chronicles and literary works, the writings of a nineteenth-century Shia feminist, a twentieth-century Iranian encyclopaedia, and others. These case studies demonstrate that Muslim sources contain valuable materials on Esther, which shed light both on the Esther story itself and on the Muslim peoples and cultures that received it. Adam J. Silverstein argues that Muslim sources preserve important pre-Islamic materials on Esther that have not survived elsewhere, some of which offer answers to ancient questions about Esther, such as the meaning of Haman's epithet in the Greek versions of the story, the reason why Mordecai refused to prostrate before Haman, and the literary context of the 'plot of the eunuchs' to kill the Persian king. Throughout the book, Silverstein shows how each author's cultural and religious background influenced his or her understanding and retelling of the Esther story. In particular, he highlights that Persian Muslims (and Jews) were often forced to reconcile or choose between the conflicting historical narratives provided by their religious and cultural heritages respectively.</note>
                <citedRange>Hey, this one has kids!</citedRange>
            </biblStruct>
            <listRelation>
                <relation active="https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/I9IEMR7Z" ref="dc:subject" type="book">
                    <desc>Esther</desc>
                </relation>
                <relation active="https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/I9IEMR7Z" ref="dc:subject" type="part">
                    <desc>Old Testament</desc>
                </relation>
                <relation active="https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/I9IEMR7Z" ref="dc:subject" type="subject">
                    <desc>Muslim reception</desc>
                </relation>
            </listRelation>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>