<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a">Biblical Predictions of the Prophet Muḥammad among the Zaydīs of Iran</title>
                <title level="j">Arabica</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="associate" ref="https://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/vevian_zaki">Vevian Zaki</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/vevian_zaki">Vevian Zaki</name>
                </respStmt>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record edited in Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/nathanpgibson">Nathan P. Gibson</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/JTZ7VIVJ/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-10-10+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-10-10+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <analytic>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Sabine</forename>
                        <surname>Schmidtke</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="a">Biblical Predictions of the Prophet Muḥammad among the Zaydīs of Iran</title>
                    <idno type="URI">https://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/JTZ7VIVJ</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/JTZ7VIVJ</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/JTZ7VIVJ</idno>
                    <ref target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/41727674"/>
                </analytic>
                <monogr>
                    <title level="j">Arabica</title>
                    <imprint>
                        <date>2012</date>
                    </imprint>
                    <biblScope unit="pp">218-266</biblScope>
                    <biblScope unit="vol">59</biblScope>
                </monogr>
                <note type="abstract">Biblical predictions of the advent of the Prophet Muḥammad are rarely adduced in the theological writings of Mu'tazilite authors and those who referred to them clearly considered this to be a secondary strategy at best. Zaydī Mu'tazilites were less hesitant than their Sunnī counterparts to employ scriptural materials. This was possibly due to the influence of the Imām al-Qāsim b. Ibrāhīm al-Rassī (d. 246/860) who was intimately familiar with Christian theological notions and with the Bible, from which he quoted freely in some of his writings. Among the Zaydīs of Iran, scriptural passages allegedly foretelling the advent of Muḥammad have been adduced by the Imām al-Mu'ayyad bi-Llāh (d. 411/1020), by his companion, the later Imām al-Muwaffaq bi-Llāh (d. after 420/1029), and by Ahmad b. Muḥammad al-Sammān (fl. early 5th/11th century). An analysis of the texts suggests that the three authors were drawing on source(s)/translation traditions preceding or parallel to that of c Alī b. Rabban al-Tabarī's (d. 251/865) al-Dīn wa-l-dawla and Ibn Qutayba's (d. 276/889) A'ldm al-nubuwwa. Les prédictions bibliques sur l'avènement du Prophète Muḥammad sont rarement mentionnées dans les écrits théologiques des auteurs mu'tazilites. Ceux qui s'y référèrent estiment clairement qu'il s'agit là, au mieux, d'une stratégie secondaire. Les Mu'tazilites zaydites se montrèrent moins hésitants que leurs confrères sunnites à employer des matériaux scripturaires. Il se peut que cela soit dû à l'influence de l'imam al-Qāsim b. Ibrāhīm al-Rassī (m. 246/860), extrêmement familier des notions de théologie chrétienne ainsi que de la Bible à laquelle il emprunta librement dans certains de ses écrits. Parmi les Zaydites d'Iran, c'est chez l'imam al-Mu'ayyad bi-Llāh (m. 411/1020), chez son compagnon, le futur imam al-Muwaffaq bi-Llāh (m. après 420/1029) et chez Aḥmad b. Muḥammad al-Sammān (en vie au début du v e /xi e siècle) que des passages des Écritures — prétendument annonciateurs de la venue de Muḥammad — se retrouvent cités. Une analyse de leurs textes suggère ques les trois auteurs puisèrent à des traditions ou à des traductions antérieures ou contemporaines aux ouvrages de ʿAlīb. Rabban al-Ṭabarī (m. 251/865), al-Dīn wa-l-dawla et d'Ibn Qutayba (m. 276/889), Aʿlām al-nubuwwa.</note>
            </biblStruct>
            <bibl type="formatted" subtype="https://www.zotero.org/styles/chicago-note-bibliography-16th-edition">
  Schmidtke, Sabine. “Biblical Predictions of the Prophet Muḥammad among the Zaydīs of Iran.” <title level="m">Arabica</title> 59, no. 3/4 (2012): 218–66. http://www.jstor.org/stable/41727674.
</bibl>
            <listRelation/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>