<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="a">Ahmad b. Mustafa Tashkubrizade's (d. 968/1561) polemical tract against Judaism</title>
                <title level="j">al-Qanṭara</title>
                <sponsor>Biblia Arabica</sponsor>
                <funder>Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</funder>
                <principal>Ronny Vollandt</principal>
                <editor role="general" ref="http://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#rvollandt">Ronny Vollandt</editor>
                <editor role="general" ref="http://biblia-arabica.com/documentation/editors.xml#ngibson">Nathan P. Gibson</editor>
                <editor role="creator" ref="https://www.zotero.org/vevian_zaki">vevian zaki</editor>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>Record added to Zotero by</resp>
                    <name ref="https://www.zotero.org/vevian_zaki">vevian zaki</name>
                </respStmt>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Biblia Arabica</authority>
                <idno type="URI">http://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/QNCHHBAT/tei</idno>
                <availability>
        <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">
            <p>Distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</p>
        </licence>
    </availability>
                <date>2018-07-06+02:00</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Born digital.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change who="http://syriaca.org/documentation/editors.xml#autogenerated" when="2018-07-06+02:00">CREATED: This bibl record was autogenerated from a Zotero record.</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <biblStruct>
                <analytic>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Sabine</forename>
                        <surname>Schmidtke</surname>
                    </author>
                    <author>
                        <forename>Camilla</forename>
                        <surname>Adang</surname>
                    </author>
                    <title level="a">Ahmad b. Mustafa Tashkubrizade's (d. 968/1561) polemical tract against Judaism</title>
                    <idno type="URI">http://biblia-arabica.com/bibl/QNCHHBAT</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/biblia_arabica/items/QNCHHBAT</idno>
                    <idno type="URI">https://www.zotero.org/groups/538215/items/QNCHHBAT</idno>
                </analytic>
                <monogr>
                    <title level="j">al-Qanṭara</title>
                    <imprint>
                        <date>June 30, 2008</date>
                    </imprint>
                    <biblScope unit="pp">79-113</biblScope>
                    <biblScope unit="vol">29</biblScope>
                </monogr>
                <note type="abstract">This article deals with a short polemical tract against Judaism written by the well-known Ottoman scholar Aḥmad Muṣṭafā Ṭāshkubrīzāde (d. 968/1560). The author uses the same arguments known to us from medieval polemics, viz. that the Torah, which was abrogated by Islam, contains references to the Prophet Muḥammad, despite the fact that it was tampered with by the Jews. In addition to the Bible, Ṭāshkubrīzāde quotes a number of later Jewish sources that add an important dimension to his tract. After a brief introduction in which the possibility of the author's indebtedness to Ibn Abī ‘Abd al-Dayyān, a Jewish convert to Islam, is discussed, an edition and translation of the text are provided.

Este artículo estudia un corto tratado de polémica en contra del judaísmo escrito por el conocido erudito otomano Aḥmad Muṣṭafā Ṭāšhkubrīzāde (m. 968/1560). El autor utiliza los mismos argumentos que conocemos de la polémica religiosa medieval, tales como que la Torah, abrogada por el Islam, contenía referencias al Profeta Muḥammad a pesar de que su texto fue corrompido por los judíos. Además de la Biblia, Ṭāšhkubrīzāde cita una serie de fuentes judías tardías que añaden una importante dimensión a este trabajo. Después de una breve introducción en que se discute la posibilidad de la deuda del autor respecto a la obra de Ibn Abī ‘Abd al-Dayyān, un converso del judaísmo al Islam, se presenta una edición y traducción del texto.</note>
            </biblStruct>
            <listRelation/>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>